Remember...
牢記
The date was April 12th.
那天是4月12日
The space shuttle is about to be launched. Vostok 1.
航太飛機沃斯托克1號即將發射
He used to launch shuttles, but still no one comes around.
他曾經發射過航太飛機，但仍然冇人來接他
A STAR FELL FROM THE SKY
流行劃過夜空
I MADE A WISH
我許下一個願望
I WISHED THEY ALL DIED
我希望他們都死了
Mom, I need to ask you something.
媽  我要問你一件事
Why did you lie that day?
你那天為什麼說謊？
You and Selim, when I asked you how that house burned down?
當我問你那所房子是怎麼被燒毀的時候  你和塞利姆為什麼說謊？
Why would I lie?
我為什麼要撒謊？
You're going to make a decision.
你要做出決定
Will I see your face again?
我會再見到你嗎？
It's Firuz! Don't shoot! I'm coming out!
是菲魯茲！別開槍！我要出來了！
I was on night duty when a man came by.
我上夜班的時候一個男人來找我
I remember everything he said to me.
我記得他對我說的一切
"You will forget about this. Or you will disappear," he said.
他說：“你會忘記這些事，否則你會消失的  ”
- Tell me you're letting me go. - Let's say I let you go.
-告訴我  你會放我走  -假設我放你走
Will everything you've done all these years also let you go?
這些年來你所做的一切會放過你嗎？
I asked you if you're mafia, son!
我問你是不是黑手黨！
Yeah. We are. So what?
是，那又怎樣？
Good. Here's your mafia.
好，這就是黑手黨的下場
PERSONAL
個人
Bro...
兄弟
This is an incredible idea, Deva.
德瓦，這真是一個不可思議的想法
- You see it, right? - Yeah. I see it.
-看到了吧 -是的
How many people have written in?
有多少人在這裏留言？
It's as if they've waited their whole lives for this moment.
好像他們已經等了一輩子了
Waiting for someone to ask them their opinion.
等待別人問他們的意見
There are some great replies here.
這裏有一些很好的回複
Here are some. Listen up.
聽著
Whom would you like Dog Slayer to kill?
你想讓狗殺手殺死誰？
He should kill the people who sit around on park benches,
他應該殺死坐在公園長椅上的人
eating nuts and scattering trash everywhere.
吃著堅果  亂扔垃圾
Here's another one.
還有這個
Wouldn't it be great if he killed the ones who refuse to stop honking?
如果他殺死不停按喇叭的人，那不是很好嗎？
It would be.
還真是不錯
Here's another one.
還有這個
You know how when you're waiting in line
你是否覺得當你排隊的時候
and the person behind you is standing too close to you?
你背後的人離你太近了嗎？
He should kill them so we can finally breathe.
他應該殺死他們，以便我們放鬆下來
Let me see.
讓我看看
"Dear Dog Slayer..."
“親愛的狗殺手”
My mom forbade me from going on the internet
“我媽媽禁止我上網”
"because I'm doing bad at school. Could you please kill my mom?"
“因為我在學校學習不好，能請你殺死我媽媽嗎？”
- So it says. - He wants him to kill his mom?
-上麵這樣寫的  -他要他殺死他的媽媽？
It seems so. Look at his nickname.
看來是的，你看他的昵稱
Vengeful generation.
複仇的一代
So this Mehmet Yurtgil went to the doctor.
所以這位穆罕默德·尤特吉爾去找過醫生
He threatened the doctor and shut him up by scaring him.
他威脅醫生並通過恐嚇使他閉嘴
And then, he forces him to write this report about Ufuk.
然後，醫生被強迫撰寫有關烏福克的報告
- Is that so? - Yes, sir.
-是嗎  -是的長官
And the first victim is this Mehmet Yurtgil.
並且第一位受害者就是穆罕默德·尤爾吉爾
You remember when I told you that I'd picked you from among 50 women?
你還記得我告訴過我我是從50位女性中選出你的嗎？
Thank you for not letting me down. I have another thing to thank you on.
謝謝你冇有讓我失望  我還有另一件事要感謝你
The other day, when we were talking in my room
前幾天，當我們在我的房間裏聊天時
and I told you that what's happening might have nothing to do with Kambura...
我告訴你發生的事情可能與坎佈拉無關
You know how you asked me for the file? How you didn't give up on it?
你知道你是怎麼問我這個文件的嗎？你怎麼不放棄呢？
Thank you for that, as well.
也謝謝你
Good job. We're getting closer.
幹得好  我們越來越接近了
What did the good sir write this time?
好先生這次寫了什麼？
They all had the same word written on them.
他們都是相同的字眼
"Personal."
“個人”
"Personal." So he killed them for his own reasons, huh?
“個人”  所以他是出於個人原因殺死了他們，是嗎？
- Seems so. - Then...
-似乎如此  -那麼……
Whom did he kill all these people for?  Who are they?
他為誰殺了這些人？他們是什麼人？
Chief, these men had 80 priors.
長官，這些人有80個前科
Accessory. Forgery. Their rap sheet is something to behold.
同謀罪  僞造罪  這些人的前科值得一看
But they're not connected to Kambura. No fingerprints, either.
但他們都與坎佈拉無關  也冇有找到任何指紋
But the crime was caught on CCTV.
但犯罪過程被監控拍了下來
Let me guess. Cat costume.
我猜一定是穿了貓服裝
Yes.
是的
We were able to follow him a long while through neighborhood shops' cameras.
我們能夠通過附近商店的攝像機跟著他走了很長時間
He went in and out of a few streets.
他進出幾條街
He acted like he wasn't sure which way he was supposed to be headed.
他的舉動就像他不確定他應該去往哪個方嚮
He went into a construction site, because that whole area is a construction site
他進入一個建築工地，因為整個區域都是一個建築工地
and there are no cameras looking inside, we lost the suspect.
而且裏麵冇有攝像頭，所以我們跟丟了
We lost him because of the urban transformation project.
由於城市改造項目  所以跟丟了
He had his escape planned.
他有逃跑計畫
Those construction sites are like black holes in the middle of our cities.
這些建築工地就像我們城市中心的黑洞
This is bad. This is really bad.
這很糟糕  這真的很糟糕
This is really bad. Everyone's getting on the ride.
這真的很糟糕  每個人都在搭順風車
Whoever has a bone to pick will shoot, kill, and blame him!
誰有骨氣，誰就開槍，誰就殺人，誰就嫁禍於他!
So we have the Kambura connection.
那麼我們怎麼與坎佈拉聯係起來
What do you think?
你怎麼看？
Tayyar Kaymak, who died in the house that night,
塔亞爾·凱馬克，那天晚上被燒死在房子裏的人
has a brother, Hamza Kaymak.
他有一個兄弟叫做哈姆薩·凱馬克
We think he might know something.
我們認為他可能知道一些事
Maybe he's the killer. Maybe he wants to avenge his brother.
也許他是殺手  也許他想為他兄弟報仇
No, sir.
不，長官
He was in prison for mugging someone while the murders were being committed.
在兇手殺人期間他因搶劫而入獄
He's in prison, huh? Fine. Alright.
他在監獄裏嗎？好吧
But he has to know something. He's Tayyar's brother after all, right?
但是他一定知道什麼事情  畢竟他是塔亞爾的兄弟，不是嗎？
We need to find out what he knows. Go to his prison and talk to him.
我們需要搞清楚他知道些什麼  去監獄和他談談
He escaped.
他越獄了
He fled the night when we were trying to get Ufuk out of Kambura.
當我們試圖將烏福克從坎佈拉開出來的時候
There's a manhunt for him right now.
現在有人在追捕他
No way...
不可能……
See, Sefa? Another escape.
看，塞法？又一次越獄
Come on, Chief. It was a lapse of judgement.
別這樣長官   那是一次錯誤的判斷
He handed himself in. How could I've known he'd try that?
他是自首的，我怎麼可能預料到他會逃跑？
Anyway. Fine. Here's what we're going to do.
好吧  總之  我們接下來這樣做
Nevra, you go after Tayyar's brother.
內芙拉，你去追捕塔亞爾的兄弟
Get print-outs of his mugshot. Spread them around.
把他的照片列印出來  分發出去
If he's out there, someone will have seen him.
如果他在外麵，有人會看到他的
Sefa, you gather more information on the house that burned down.
塞法，你去收集有關被燒毀房屋的更多信息
Anyone who remembers or knows something about that night...
任何記得或知道那晚事情的人
Get the whole Kambura in here for interrogation.
把坎佈拉的所有人都詢問一遍
- Let's go. - Right away, Chief.
-行動  -是的  長官
This is not going to work out.
這樣不行的
What if I get really sick before I do all these people in?
如果我在殺掉所有人之前就病的不行了怎麼辦？
Then...
然後
First...
首先
Hello.
你好
Do you have a last wish?
你有遺願嗎？
No?
冇有？
You do?
你有？
Forgive me, but I don't give a toss.
原諒我，但我不在乎
Hello?
你好？
Yes?
是？
Who?
誰？
Who, did you say?
你說誰？
- Hamza Kaymak, right? - Yes, Ates, it's really urgent.
-哈姆薩·凱馬克，對嗎？-是的，阿提斯，這真的很緊急
Don't worry. His photos will be everywhere in half an hour.
別擔心，半小時之內到處都是他的照片
Thank you.
謝謝
When will I see you?
我什麼時候能見到你？
I don't know when I'll be able to get out of here.
我不知道我什麼時候可以離開這裏
Do you go home at all?
你有回過家嗎？
- Sometimes, yes. - Can I come?
-有時候回去，是的  -我能去嗎？
Come.
來吧
Alright.
好的
- Firuz... - Yeah?
-菲魯茲  -什麼事？
What do you have?
你有什麼？
Firuz, this won't get me in trouble, right?
菲魯茲，這不會給我帶來麻煩吧？
Come on, Fiko! You've known me for years.
得了吧  菲科！你認識我多少年了
Relax. You'll be fine.
放鬆  你會冇事的
What is this? What did you find?
這是什麼？你找到了什麼？
I found some blood on the crime scene that doesn't belong to the victims.
我在犯罪現場發現了一些不屬於受害者的鮮血
Probably belongs to the suspect.
可能屬於嫌疑犯
- Is this the DNA report on it? - Yes.
-這是DNA報告嗎？  -是的
Good.
好
Here.
給你
Don't spend it all in one place.
不要把所有的錢都花在一個地方
This isn't in the file you provided the others, right?
這不在你提供給其他人的文件中，對嗎？
- You threw it out, right? - Yes. I did.
-你把這些挑出來了？  -是的
- I'll see you around. - Firuz. How's your boy doing?
-回見  -菲魯茲你兒子怎麼樣？
The same. No change.
老樣子
What's this?
這是什麼？
Deva, take a look at this. Come here.
德瓦，過來看看這個
Isn't that the corpse that was found in the jungle?
那不是在叢林中發現的屍體嗎？
Salim or something?
薩利姆還是誰？
But what are they doing there?
但是他們在那裏做什麼？
Who are they?
他們是什麼人？
I don't know. Respond to them and let's get acquainted.
我不知道  回複他們  認識一下
One second. One second, miss.
等等，小姐
Calm down for one second.
冷靜一下
You saw the man from the photos, right?
你看到了照片中那個人，對不對？
Alright.
好的
Where did you see him?
你在哪裏看到他的？
In a dream?
在夢中？
You saw him in a dream.
你在夢中看到他
Sweet dreams, miss.
祝你好夢，小姐
- This is impossible. - Be patient. Something might turn up.
-真不可思議  -耐心一點  可能會有好事發生
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
I'm making a list of the Kamburan gentry.
我正在列出坎佈拉人的名單
Tomorrow is the Kambura Day at the station.
明天去坎佈拉
I might tell them I'm their new leader.
我可能會告訴他們我是他們的新領導人
Hello? Connect them.
餵？接進來
Nevra, I'm calling your mom's husband in, as well.
內芙拉，我也會叫你媽媽的丈夫
I'm listening, sir.
先生，我在聽
Where did you see him?
你在哪裏看到他的？
When?
什麼時候？
Please stop wasting my time.
請不要浪費我的時間
Ayhan?
艾漢
- Ayhan, good luck with all this. - Thanks, Agah.
-艾漢，祝你一切順利  -謝謝，阿加
We're doing our best to tidy up.
我們正在盡力整理
I'm sorry about last night.
昨晚我很抱歉
You join us once in a blue moon, I wish it hadn't been so unpleasant.
你難得參加我們的活動，但願並冇有那麼令人不愉快
It wasn't unpleasant. It was a proper disaster.
冇有不愉快  這是一場真正的災難
What was that? I'm so glad we up and left.
那是什麼？我很高興我們起身離開了
I wouldn't want to get beat up. I had a lady friend with me, too.
我也不想被打  我還有一個女伴和我一起
We were so scared.
我們好害怕
What business do you have with such men?
你和這些男人有什麼關係？
Don't worry, Agah. There's nothing left to be scared of.
別擔心，阿加冇有什麼可害怕的
What do you mean? What if they come back?
你是什??麼意思，如果他們回來了怎麼辦？
They were shot that night. All three are dead.
他們當晚被槍殺了  三個人都死了
No way!
不是吧！
Really. Not everyone's like us, after all.
畢竟，不是每個人都像我們一樣
They must've gone after the wrong types.
他們一定是找了錯誤的目標
Tried to extort him, and got shot.
試圖勒索他，反被槍殺
Istanbul has become unrecognizable.
伊斯坦佈爾變得麵目全非
It shouldn't be this easy to kill people.
殺人不應該那麼容易
Look how relaxed you are, talking about it.
看看你有多輕鬆的談論這件事
I don't recognize Istanbul anymore. Especially not Beyoglu.
我已經不認識伊斯坦佈爾了，尤其是貝尤魯
Oh, that old Beyoglu... That dear old Beyoglu...
哦，那個老貝尤魯  那個親愛的老貝尤魯
What can I say? When you're right, you're right.
我能說什麼？如果你是對的，你就是對的
Sadly, we've been getting reports
可悲的是，我們收到很多報告
of mistreatment of residents from nursing homes more and more lately.
療養院對住戶的虐待最近越來越多
However, we're at a stellar nursing home right now.
但是，我們現在是一家一流的養老院
We have a resident with us. Let's ask her some questions.
這有一位住戶  讓我們問她一些問題
Are you happy here? Would you like to say anything?
你在這裏開心嗎？你想說什麼嗎？
I turned 65.
我65歲了
You look great. I hope you see many more years yet.
你看起來很棒  我希望你能長命百歲
On my last birthday, I made another wish.
在上一個生日，我又許了一個願望
- Like a child. - That's great.
-像個孩子一樣  -太好了
It was another impossible wish, of course.
當然，這是另一個不可能的願望
It might not be. I hope it comes true.
也許是不可能的，但我希望成真
You know what I wished for?
你知道我想要什麼嗎？
To become a good person.
成為一個好人
- Great. We should all aspire to that. - She remembers everything.
-太好了，我們都應該朝這個方嚮努力  -她記得一切
What is it, Agah? You're awfully interested in her.
阿加  你到底對她有什麼興趣
No. I'm more interested in the TV.
不，我對電視更感興趣
Mine's getting old. I might get one of these.
我老了  我可能會買一臺
Do you like it here? How long have you been here?
你喜歡這裏嗎？你來這裏多久了？
It's crystal clear.
水晶般清澈
Whenever I come here,
每當我來這裏
something's on the TV.
電視上都有節目
- Anyway... Good luck to you. - Thanks. Take care of yourself.
-反正祝你好運  -謝謝  照顧好自己
Come on. Tidy it up. We're about to open back up.
整理一下，我們要重新開張了
Come on. We need to tidy the place up. Customers are on the way.
來吧，我們需要整理一下  客人就快來了
So with Alzheimer's, let's say it's at an advanced stage.
對於老年癡呆癥患者，如果處於晚期
It's all over. The patient remembers nothing.
一切都結束了  病人什麼都不記得
Completely disconnected from the world.
完全脫離世界
- Yes? - Might they suddenly remember?
-嗯？-他們會突然想起來嗎？
Might they get their memory back?
他們會恢複記憶嗎？
Is that possible? Is that a possibility? Does that happen?
那有可能嗎？有可能發生嗎？
Why are you asking me this? You're not at that stage yet.
你為什麼要問我這個？你還冇到那個階段
It's too early to be worrying about stuff like this.
現在擔心這樣的事情還為時過早
I'm pondering every eventuality.
我正在考慮所有的可能
It's worth hoping for. Is it possible at all?
值得期待，那有可能嗎？
I realize that I'll forget everything some day.
我意識到有一天我會忘記一切
But I'm asking you if this is a possibility.
但是我問你這是否有可能
Agah!
阿加！
Alzheimer's...
老年癡呆癥
Is still shrouded in mystery.
仍然籠罩在神秘之中
Each person is an exception.
每個人都是例外
Each case progresses differently.
每個病人的發展情況都不一樣
But in general, that's outside the realm of possibility.
但總的來說，幾乎不可能
Possibilities, exceptions. You're not saying anything!
可能性，例外情況呢？  你什麼也冇說！
I'm asking you if it's possible or not!
我問你是否可能！
Remember when I told you about sudden bursts of anger?
還記得我告訴過你關於突然爆發的憤怒嗎？
I don't want to talk about my bursts! Answer me!
我不想談論我的憤怒！回答我！
You're having one of those bursts right now.
你現在正遇到這些突發事件中的一種情況
Because you don't answer!
因為你不回答！
Because your question doesn't have an answer!
因為你的問題冇有答案！
Forgive me.
原諒我
I mean...
我的意思是
Even if there are no known cases...
即使冇有已知病例
It's possible.
但這是有可能的
How about you relax now?
你現在放鬆一下怎麼樣？
Take a few deep breaths through the nose. Relax...
深呼吸  放鬆一下……
I can relax later! I can't relax now! I have work to do!
我以後可以放鬆！我現在不能放鬆！我還有工作要做！
- I'm leaving, with your permission. - Agah...
-我要離開，如果你允許的話  -阿加
Yes?
是？
- Are you up to something? - I don't... What do you mean?
-你在忙什麼？-我不是……什麼意思？
Have you stopped taking your medication?
你已經停止服藥了嗎？
Of course not. I'm taking my meds.
當然不是  我正在服用藥物
- Are you sure? - Yes.
-確定嗎-是的
Alright. For your next appointment, please bring Zuhal along.
好吧，下次預約時，請帶上祖哈爾
Excuse me? Why?
不好意思？為什麼？
Is Zuhal the patient or am I? Why does she need to be here?
祖哈爾是患者還是我是患者？她為什麼需要在這裏？
Alright, fine.
好  好
Fine. I'll bring my daughter along.
好  我帶女兒來
How will I get in?
我怎麼進去？
Where will I get in?
從哪裏進去？
You poor Agah.
可憐的阿加
How will you...
你怎樣……
Of course you can't.
當然不能
Serves you right for coming so unprepared.
你真是活該，冇做準備就來了
You're not about to sprout wings and jump over the fence, are you?
你不會長出翅膀來跳過圍牆  對吧？
Hello again.
再次問好
You told me to come see you if I needed anything.
你告訴我如果有需要時就找你
No matter what, you said.
不管需要什麼
I need something.
我需要個東西
Could you please die for me?
你願意為我去死嗎？
What are these?
這些是什麼？
The best picnics...
最好的野餐
Are those had at home, Nevra.
都是在家裏吃的
I'll take that. Come in.
我拿進來
- Any news on Tayyar's brother? - No.
-有關於塔亞爾兄弟的消息嗎？-冇有
There are, actually. Some woman called.
其實有幾個女人打電話來
Told me she saw him in her dreams.
告訴我她在夢中看到他
- How does that sound? - Sounds great.
-聽起來怎麼樣？-聽起來很棒
It's better than nothing.
總比冇有好
When did you move in here?
你什麼時候搬來的？
As you can see, I never really did.
如你所見，我還冇真正搬進來
It's been like this for like six months.
像這樣六個月了
I think it looks nice.
我覺得很好看
Maybe I should decorate my place after yours.
也許我應該用你的房間來裝飾我的房間
I think that's a great idea. Everything's all tidied up, you see?
我認為這是個好主意，一切都整理好了，你知道嗎？
Plus, when you want to move out, you don't have to do any packing up.
另外，當你要搬走的時候都不需要打包
Why? Are you planning to go somewhere?
為什麼？你打算去某個地方嗎？
I always go somewhere, Ates.
我總是去某個地方，阿提斯
You can't tell from the outside, but I very often leave my body.
你看不出來，但我經常離開我的身體
- It's your turn. - What turn?
-輪到你了-輪到什麼了？
I've told you everything about me.
我已經告訴過你關於我的一切
Told you I've been rotting for years.
告訴你我已經腐爛多年了
That all I want is to become that old Ates again.
我想要的就是再次成為那個以前的阿提斯
That Ates who just got out of college.
那個剛從大學畢業的阿提斯
That Ates who still believes in journalism.
仍然相信新聞的阿提斯
I've shown you all my scars. Let you see all my pain.
我已經給你看了我所有的傷疤  讓你看到了我所有的痛苦
It's your turn to tell me.
該你告訴我了
First, tell me why you knocked on my door that night.
首先，告訴我那天晚上你為什麼來我家
You know how you say...
你知道當你說……
That all you want is to become that old Ates again...
你想要的就是再次成為那個以前的阿提斯
I'm the exact opposite.
我正好相反
What I fear most is becoming the old Nevra.
我最擔心的是成為以前的內芙拉
Why?
為什麼？
I think...
我認為……
I don't know how to co-exist with people.
我不知道如何與人共存
How to talk to people.
如何與人交談
What to do with friends.
與朋友做什麼
How to spend time with a boyfriend.
如何與男友共度時光
How to manage the space between you and someone else.
如何管理你與他人之間的空間
I don't know how to do any of that.
我不知道該怎麼做
But I've always pretended to know.
但是我一直假裝知道
And I was always wrong.
而且我總是錯的
I've had relationships I really didn't want at all.
我有談過戀愛  但我真的根本不想談
I've had friends that I never liked.
我有一些我從未喜歡過的朋友
I couldn't say no to anyone.
我不能拒絕任何人
I don't know why,
我不知道為什麼
but I always cared so much about what people thought about me.
但我總是非常關心人們對我的看法
As thought I had to make everyone happy.
以為我不得不讓每個人都開心
Because...
因為
You're...
你是
Good.
好人
No.
不是
Because I'm weak.
因為我軟弱
I'm so weak, in fact,
我實在很軟弱
that I'm scared of opening those boxes and running into the old Nevra in them.
我不敢打開那些盒子，然後又變成以前的內芙拉
I knocked on your door that night,
那天晚上我敲了你的門，
because I felt really lonely that night.
因為那天晚上我真的很寂寞
The old Nevra, the one I never want to become again,
那個我不想再成為的老內芙拉
used to fling herself into some guy's arms
過去常常把自己扔進別人的懷裏
whenever she felt lonely.
每當她感到孤獨時
Ce... Ce...
塞……
Cemil!
塞米爾！
Whom was I with on that night?
那天晚上我和誰在一起？
You, or...
是你  還是
The old Nevra?
曾經的內芙拉？
The old Nevra...
曾經的內芙拉……
The old Nevra
曾經的內芙拉
would probably be with someone else right now.
現在可能會和其他人在一起
That's what I ran away from, Ates.
那是我逃離的地方，阿提斯
Cemil, he has a gun, Cemil.
塞米爾，他有槍，塞米爾
Cemil...
塞米爾
Cemil!
塞米爾！
- You stay inside. - OK, be careful.
-你待在裏麵  -好吧，你小心
I ran away from myself.
我逃離了自己
That's why I wanted a new life.
這就是為什麼我想要新的生活
A life where no one knew me.
冇有人認識我的生活
To be more accurate...
更準確地說……
A life without people who think they know me.
是冇有那些自以為了解我的人的生活
That's why I resigned and started over.
這就是為什麼我辭職並重新開始
Cemil!
塞米爾！
Cemil...
塞米爾
There's no one here.
這裏冇有人
There was.
剛剛還有
It was him.
是他
- Who? - The serial killer.
-誰？-連環殺手
He's on everywhere. He wears a cat costume.
他穿著貓服裝到處殺人
He was there. He had a gun in his hand.
他剛剛就在那裏  手裏拿著槍
- But there's no one around. - He must've run away.
-但是冇有人  -他一定已經逃跑了
Maybe you scared him.
也許你嚇到他了
Funny.
真可笑
Do you realize, Zuhal, that you saved my life?
祖哈爾，你有冇有意識到你救了我的命？
If I'd answered the door, I doubt he'd have been scared of me.
如果是我開的門  我想我絕對不會嚇跑他
- Let's go inside. - Sure. Let's.
-我們進去吧  -好
Cemil!
塞米爾！
This is the first time I'm telling someone all this.
這是我第一次和別人說這些話
Strange, right?
奇怪吧
You chasing yourself,  and me running away from myself.
你追逐自己，我逃避自己
That's exactly why, I think...
我認為這就是……
We'll be a perfect couple.
我們將成為完美情侶的原因
- You know our first order of business? - What?
-你知道我們的首要任務是什麼嗎？-什麼？
You didn't eat anything. Why aren't you eating?
你什麼都冇吃  為什麼不吃？
Have you spoken to your mom?
你跟你媽媽聊過嗎？
She texted last night. Staying over at a friend's or something.
昨晚她發簡訊住在朋友還是什麼人的家
- She should be back today. - Who is this friend?
-她今天應該回來  -這個朋友是誰？
- I don't know. - Aren't you curious?
-我不知道-你不好奇嗎？
She's an adult. Why would I be?
她是一個成年人，我為什麼要好奇？
What do you mean, why? Is this a hotel?
你什麼意思，為什麼？這是酒店嗎？
Check in or out whenever you'd like.
隨時簽入或簽出
You do it all the time.
你一直是這樣啊
We don't mind you staying at your girlfriend's.
我們不介意你呆在女友的家裏
Stop running your mouth.
閉嘴
You're being ridiculous.
你真可笑
- Are you mad about something? - Why would I be mad!
-你在生什麼氣嗎？-為什麼我會生氣！
She should've let us know. "I'll be here. I'll be back by this time."
她應該讓我們知道  “我在這裏，我會回來的”
Are you talking to me, or are you staring at that screen?
你是在跟我說話，還是在盯著那個熒幕？
I can do both.
同時
No you can't listen and do that at the same time. Drop it.
不行，你不能邊聽我說話還邊玩手機
Fine. I've dropped it.
好吧，我不玩了
- What's that? - What's what?
-那是什麼？-什麼？
- That. Let me see that. - Here...
-那讓我看看  -給……
- What's this? - You're completely oblivious then, huh?
-這是什麼？-你都忘了嗎？
You don't watch the news?
你冇看新聞嗎？
He's a serial killer. The first real Turkish serial killer.
他是連環殺手  第一個真正的土耳其連環殺手
How do you know it's a he? It might be a woman.
你怎麼知道是他？也可能是女人
That's possible, of course.
當然有可能
Why did you stick that on there?
你為什麼要貼在那裏？
Because he's doing incredible stuff.
因為他在做不可思議的事情
What's incredible about killing people?
殺人有什麼不可思議的？
Depends on who you're killing.
那取決於你要殺誰
Good morning.
早上好
They received another tip. It seems legit this time.
他們收到一個情報，這次看起來很可靠
There's nothing to eat around the house except for our picnic's leftovers.
除了野餐的剩菜，家裏冇有任何吃的東西
I'll be fine. Go save the world so I can write about it later.
我會冇事的，去拯救世界吧，以便我以後寫文章
I'm going.
我走了
Came all the way to my front door.
一路來到我的前門
To the house.
到這裏
To my house.
到我家
I knew this was going to happen.
我知道這會發生
I knew it.
我就知道
If you're killing Kamburans, you're going to end up at my door sooner or later.
如果要殺坎佈蘭人，兇手遲早要來到我家門口
What am I supposed to do now? Tell me.
我現在該怎麼辦？
Whom do I bury and where? Give me something.
我該埋葬誰，埋在哪裏？給我些東西
We have the DNA report. I have a connection in the lab.
我們有DNA報告  我在實驗室裏有關係
He gave me the file without the others knowing.
他把文件給了我，其他人都不知道
Run it against the DNA of 80 million people.
從8000萬人的DNA中找到他
What's this guy's beef with Kambura?
這個人和坎佈拉有什麼過節？
What's your people doing there?
你的人在那裏做什麼？
There's this burnt-down house in Kambura.
在坎佈拉有一座被燒毀的房子
They're looking for the brother of the man who died in the fire.
他們正在尋找在大火中喪生的人的兄弟
Yeah. Hamza.
是哈姆薩
- Mister Hamza Kaymak. - Yes, that's his name.
-哈姆薩·凱馬克先生  -是的  就是他
- He's a fugitive. Escaped from prison. - I know. Because I arranged it.
-他是越獄的逃犯  -我知道，是我安排的
Hamza doesn't know about that part, of course. He wouldn't even know me.
哈姆薩不知道那些事情，他甚至都不認識我
What is it, Firuz? Why are you surprised?
怎麼了菲魯茲？為什麼感到驚訝？
You thought I didn't have other friends working in other places?
你以為我冇有在其他地方工作的朋友嗎？
Is that what you thought?
你是這樣想的嗎？
Do you know where Hamza is now?
你知道哈姆薩現在在哪裏嗎？
Gratitude is a dying concept these days. I don't know where he is, sadly.
如今，感恩已是一個逐漸消失的概念，我也不知道他在哪裏
That ingrate called Hamza ran away from the people who broke him out.
那個叫哈姆薩的罪犯逃離了讓他越獄的人
Why did you get him out of prison, then?
那你為什麼把他從監獄裏救出來？
Because I knew you'd fail with Ufuk,
因為我知道你搞不定烏福克
I decided to take matters into my own hands.
所以我決定自己動手
Fine, but what does Ufuk have to do with Hamza?
好吧，但是烏福克與哈姆薩有什麼關係？
Firuz, the less you know,
菲魯茲，你所了解的越少
the easier you'll sleep.
睡得越香
That way, you won't come to me asking me to let you go.
這樣，你就不會來找我放過你
Got that?
知道了？
We have lots of people coming in from Kambura today.
今天有很多來自坎佈拉的人
Looking into the burnt-down house.
調查被燒毀的房子
You know what we were just talking about, Zuhal?
你知道我們在說什麼嗎，祖哈爾？
Why do you think he lowered his gun when he saw you?
為什麼看到你時他會放下槍？
He didn't want to kill you. He was here for me.
他不想殺了你  他是沖我來的
Why didn't he come inside?
他為什麼不進屋？
I mean...
我的意思是……
I don't know.
我不知道
- Don't you find it strange? - Very strange.
-你不覺得奇怪嗎？-很奇怪
Maybe he changed his mind. I don't know.
也許他改變了主意  我不知道
Isn't it possible that he regretted it?
是否有可能他後悔了？
It's not that easy, taking a life.
殺人並不容易
Well, Zuhal, that depends on whom you're killing.
好吧，祖哈爾，這取決於你要殺死誰
Yes, Sungur.
嗯  桑古爾
Why did that house burn down? Who burned it down?
那房子為什麼被燒毀了？誰把它燒了？
I don't know who burned it down,
我不知道是誰燒了它，
but we all thought Tayyar was a thief.
但我們都以為塔亞爾是個小偷
I mean...
我的意思是……
Word was going around.
消息四處流傳
Thieves drive me up the walls.
小偷把我逼瘋了
If he came to us, telling us needed help, we would've given him everything.
如果他來找我們，告訴我們他需要幫助，我們會盡力幫助他
But stealing? Come on.
但是你非要偷東西？
We saw a crowd gathering around the house.
我們看到一群人圍在房子周圍
So I went over with the kids.
所以我和孩子們一起過去了
Suddenly, a fire started.
突然就起火了
We wanted to put it out...
我們想把火撲滅
- But couldn't. - You couldn't.
-但是不行 -你做不到
- Excuse me. - Hi.
-打擾一下-嗨
I'm looking for Kamuran G?zcü. They told me he worked here.
我在找卡穆蘭·蓋茲奇  有人告訴我他在這裏工作
Brother Kamuran? Over there.
卡穆蘭？在那邊
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
-謝謝-不客氣
Good day. Murder Bureau. Nevra Y?lmaz.
你好  我是來自兇殺科的內芙拉·艾爾瑪斯
I'm looking for Kamuran G?zcü.
我在找卡穆蘭·蓋茲奇
Come on in. I'm Kamuran.
來吧，我就是卡穆蘭
Take a seat.
坐
You said you knew Hamza Kaymak.
你說你知道哈姆薩·凱馬克
I know him, of course.
我當然認識他
He sat right there just yesterday. Helped us clean the mussels.
他昨天就坐在那裏幫助我們清理了貽貝
Then he got word of something and started panicking.
然後他聽到一些話就開始驚慌
He apparently talked to someone last night. He was gone in the morning.
他昨晚跟某人交談，今早就不見了
- Where might he have gone? - I wouldn't know.
-他可能去了哪裏？-我不知道
Bulgaria, Greece... The guy he talked to smuggles people.
保加利亞，希臘……與他交談的人是人販子
One of the boys overheard them.
我們的一個孩子偷聽到了
And Hamza...
哈姆薩……
Probably to pay that smuggler, he took all the money we kept here.
可能是為了付錢給人犯，他拿走了我們留在這裏的所有錢
Look... I implore you.
我懇求你
If you find that man, ask him about our money.
如果找到那個人，請把我們的錢要回來
It was for their honest work.
那是他們的血汗錢
I don't remember anything, son. I wouldn't know anything at all.
我什麼都不記得了，孩子 我一點都不知道
Selim... Uncle Selim.
塞利姆……  塞利姆叔叔
You must've overheard something.
你一定聽說過
You weren't there that night. I know.
我知道你那天晚上不在
But didn't people talk about it around Kambura? They must have.
但是人們冇有談論這件事嗎？一定有人說起過
Well...
好
Our people don't like foreigners.
我們那裏的人不喜歡外國人
Not me, of course. But...
當然不是我
I don't discriminate at all.
我一點也不歧視
But... I mean...
但是我的意思是
- That might be why. - Because he was a foreigner.
-原因可能是  -因為他是外國人
Sure.
當然
Foreigners are different to us.
外國人與我們不同
Different to us. Yes.
是與我們不同
Ates...
阿提斯
You ran a story on human smugglers.
你寫過一篇關於人販的文章
It had interviews and stuff in it. I need to get a hold of one of them.
裏麵有採訪之類的東西  我需要找到他們中的一人
I don't care who.
我不在乎是誰
Alright. I'll see you there.
好吧，我在那裏見
Nobody put chains on anything.
冇人用鐵鏈鎖門
Who told you they put chains on the windows and doors?
誰告訴你有人用鐵鏈鎖住了門窗？
It was all ablaze when we arrived.
我們到的時候全是大火
Ufuk was crying out, trying to get inside.
烏福克哭了，想進去救人
We did our best, but it was impossible.
我們已經盡力了，但那是不可能的
We were torn between holding Ufuk back and trying to put out the fire.
我們在阻止烏福克和試圖撲滅大火之間左右為難。
That's when something fell on Ufuk's head. A beam or something.
就在那時  一根橫梁掉下來砸中烏福克的頭
He was already a half-wit.
他本來就是個笨蛋
After that, he became really strange.
在那之後，他變得很奇怪
What were you doing there?
你當時在哪裏幹什麼？
Ufuk had been talking about it a while.
烏福克一直在說那些話
Saying he'd burn that place down, saying he'd kill Tayyar.
說是他燒掉了房子  是他殺掉了塔亞爾一家
When we saw Ufuk running to the house, we followed him.
當我們看到烏福克奔嚮房屋時，我們緊跟著他
To stop him from doing something stupid. But we couldn't.
阻止他做一些愚蠢的事情，但是我們不能
Why did Ufuk want to kill Tayyar?
烏福克為什麼要殺死塔亞爾一家？
Because he was a thief, or because he was Romani? Why?
是因為他是小偷，還是因為他是吉普賽人？為什麼？
He's mad, I'm telling you. You can't ask a madman why he did what.
他瘋了，我告訴你  你不能問一個瘋子做事的原因
Tayyar might've given him dirty looks, for all I know.
就我所知，塔亞可能冇給他好臉色
It's a small place.
這是個小地方
There's nothing to do but bicker.
除了爭吵外別無他法
You think being involved with my daughter makes you immortal?
你以為和我女兒在一起就能不死了嗎？
Alright.
好的
If you're not going to bleed for now,
如果你暫時不死
whom would you like to take your place?
誰來代替你？
How about your blood brother?
你該死的兄弟怎麼樣？
That works, right? That works beautifully.
那行得通，對嗎？那行得通
I think that would be so poetic.
我認為那太詩意了
Hello.
你好
Who are you looking for.
你在找誰
- We're looking for Anchor Rü?tü. - I don't know him.
-我們在找呂泰-我不認識他
They told us everyone in Kumkap? would know him.
有人告訴我們在庫姆卡皮的每個人都認識他
Especially you.
尤其是你
There must've been a mistake.
肯定是誤會
I don't know anything. I don't know any Rü?tü.
我什麼都不知道  我不認識這個人
We aren't after you. Just tell me where Anchor Rü?tü is.
我們不是沖你來的，隻需告訴我呂泰在哪裏
- There's this street. - Where is it?
-這條街-在哪裏？
You have a deal.
成交
Anchor Rü?tü?
呂泰？
Yes? What do you want?
是的  你想要什麼
I want this man. His name is Hamza Kaymak.
我需要一個名叫哈姆薩·凱馬克的人
What does it have to do with me?
這跟我有什麼關係
He paid a smuggler to take him across the border.
他付錢給走私犯帶他過境
Why would I know about smugglers?
我怎麼會知道走私犯？
- Aren't you a smuggler? - What are you talking about? No.
-你不走私嗎？-你在說什麼？當然不是
I'm actually really calm by nature.
我天生真的很鎮定
I don't like getting mad.
我不喜歡生氣
But I'm in a real hurry. Would you like to see me get mad in a hurry?
但是我真的很著急，你想看到我著急的樣子嗎？
What if you did?
如果我想呢？
What would I do...
我該怎麼做……
I might start with making you eat the shells, for a start.
我可能首先要讓你個子彈
Do you have the license plate down? Alright.
車牌記下來了嗎
Announce it over the radio.
通過廣播宣佈
The white minivan will be leaving Tophane in two hours.
白色小型貨車將在兩個小時內離開托普哈內
It's carrying illegal aliens and the fugitive Hamza Kaymak.
它攜帶著非法移民和在逃的哈姆薩·凱馬克
I'm sending you all the info. I'm on my way.
我現在把細節發給你  我正在路上
Nevra...
內芙拉
Did you just point a gun at a man for throwing nuts on the ground?
你是不是剛剛因為一個人把堅果殼扔在地上就用槍指著他？
I can do you one better.
我可以做得更好
I saw a bull in my dream the other day.
前幾天我夢見公牛
I pointed my gun at that poor creature.
我用槍指著那頭可憐的牛
Um...
嗯……
I should head to the paper.
我要去報社了
I'll clean up my office a bit.
去收拾一下我的事務室
Thank you.
謝謝
I hope you find what you're looking for.
我希望你能找到想要的東西
I already have.
已經找到了
- What happened next? - Next, nothing...
-接下來發生了什麼？-接下來什麼都冇發生
He pointed his gun at me.
他用槍指著我
He took a good look at me, and lowered his gun.
他看著我，放下了槍
I shut the door, of course.
當然  我關上了門
When we went looking for him, he was gone.
當我們去尋找他時，他走了
- You didn't call the cops? - Of course we did. Of course!
-你冇給警察打電話嗎？-當然報警了！
You must've been so scared.
你一定很害怕
It was really scary in the moment.
當時真的很恐怖
But thinking about it now...
但是現在回想一下
There was this moment when he took a good look at me...
在那一刻，他看著我的時候……
It went on for a few seconds. I felt something...
持續了幾秒鍾  我感覺到了一些東西……
- I felt something really strange. - What did you feel?
-我覺得有些奇怪-你感覺到了什麼？
I mean... It was almost like...
我的意思是……有點像……
Like I was sure he'd never hurt me.
像是我確定他永遠都不會傷害我
It was so strange.
好奇怪
Yes. It really is.
是的，確實是
I mean, my whole life,
我是說，我的一生
I've never been so sure that someone wasn't going to hurt me.
我從未如此確定某人不會傷害我
Do you get what I'm saying? Never!
你明白我的意思嗎？
No matter whom! Except for you, of course.
不管是誰，除了你，當然
But look... Look, this is burned onto my mind.
但是，你看，這件事已經深深印在了我的腦海中
I'm really little. Eight years old. Maybe nine.
我當時真的很小  八歲也許九歲
We're going on vacation.
我們要去渡假
My dad told me he'd teach me how to jump from the pier.
爸爸告訴我，他會教我如何從碼頭上跳下來
I'm on the pier.
我在碼頭上
My dad's in the water. He's gesturing me, telling me to jump.
我爸爸在水中他在打手勢我，告訴我跳
"Come on, jump." But I can't jump. I couldn't do it.
“來吧，跳吧”  但是我不敢跳，我做不到
I felt my father wouldn't be able to protect me.
我覺得我父親無法保護我
Do you get what I'm saying? It felt as though...
你明白我的意思嗎？就好像……
As though he could hurt me, albeit unintentionally.
好像他會傷害我，盡管是無意的
As though if I were to drown, he wouldn't be able to rescue me.
好像我要淹死了，他也無法解救我
If something were to happen to me, he wouldn't...
如果我發生什麼事，他不會……
I couldn't trust my father!
我不能相信我的父親！
I couldn't trust my father on that day!
那天我不能相信我的父親！
But whatever it was that was inside that cat...
但是那隻貓裏麵的東西
I trusted that thing, Deva!
我相信他  德瓦！
Could he be someone you know, mom?
媽媽，他有可能是你認識的人嗎？
- Or might he know you? - Don't be silly.
-也許他認識你？-說什麼傻話
- I wish you did. - Where's your grandfather?
-我希望你認識他  -你祖父在哪裏？
- Huh? - I asked you where your grandfather is.
-嗯？-我問你你祖父在哪裏
He might be with his girlfriend. I don't know.
他可能和他的女朋友在一起  我不知道
Oh, Deva...
天啊  德瓦……
Hello!
你好！
- Is there anybody there? - I'll be right there.
-有人嗎？-我馬上來
Hello. How can I help you?
你好，請問什麼事？
I was looking for...
我正尋找……
I don't know, a small houseplant.
我不知道，小小的室內植物
Agah?
阿加？
- Agah Beyoglu? - Yes?
-阿加·貝尤魯？-嗯？
Forgive me, I'm not sure I remember you.
原諒我，我不確定我是否記得你
It's Tayfun, Cemil's friend! From Kambura!
我是塞米爾的朋友  我叫泰豐  來自坎佈拉！
Tay...
泰……
Tayfun! Is that you? No way!
泰豐！是你嗎？
- What a coincidence! - You haven't changed one bit.
-真是巧合！-你一點都冇變
- You're still as handsome as ever. - Stop it. I'm an old man now.
-你仍然像以前一樣英俊  -別說了，我現在是個老人
How are you doing? What are you doing here?
你最近好嗎？你在這裏做什麼？
Not much. I own this whole area. I cultivate all kinds of plants.
還行  這塊地是我的，我在這裏種各種各樣的植物
How nice. How...
真好……
I was passing by and I needed some plants for the house.
我路過這裏，需要一些室內植物
When I saw this place, I decided to stop by.
當我看到這個地方時，我決定來看看
- What a coincidence. - Don't worry, I've got you.
-太巧了  -別擔心，我來幫你
You used to take such good care of us.
你以前很照顧我們
Do you remember all those meals you bought for Cemil and I?
你還記得你為我和塞米爾買的那些飯嗎？
We were dirt-poor students back then.
那時我們是貧民窟的學生
Come on. Take a seat. Make yourself at home.
快坐吧  像在自己家一樣
You must be busy. I wouldn't want to impose.
你一定很忙  我不想耽誤你時間
Don't be ridiculous. I've sent the guys home.
別說笑了  我已經把他們送回家了
It's almost closing time. Come on. Let's catch up.
快到關門的時間了  來吧   我們好好聊聊
- Come on. - OK, then.
-來-好吧
What a coincidence. It's a small world, I'm telling you.
真是巧合  世界真小啊
We have the vehicle in our sights. It's headed right to here.
我們看到那輛車了  它直接開來這裏
Alright. Finish the paperwork first.
好，先完成文書工作
Don't let them suspect anything. He might be armed.
不要讓他們起疑心  他可能有武器
Of course.
當然
Follow the vehicle, but keep your distance.
跟隨車輛，但要保持距離
- Thank you. You're so kind. - Of course.
-謝謝你這麼好  -當然
So? Do you and Cemil still see each other?
那你和塞米爾經常見麵嗎？
Cemil's too busy. He's become an important man.
塞米爾太忙了  他是個重要人物
He stops by now and again.
他偶爾過來看看
- Would you mind if I had some raki? - Of course.
-你介意我喝點紅酒嗎？-當然不
- It goes down well at this time of day. - Of course.
-每天的這個時候喝點酒最好了  -當然
- Helps me clear my head. - Enjoy yourself.
-幫我清理頭腦  -盡情享受
- You prefer coffee, right? - Yes. Thank you.
-你喜歡喝咖啡吧？-是的  謝謝你
You could join me, though. Would you like a glass?
你要喝一杯嗎？
No. I shouldn't.
不，我不喝
The other day, I was visiting a friend...
前幾天，我去拜訪一位朋友……
He set a beautiful table and brought out a bottle of raki.
他擺好桌子，拿出一瓶紅酒
We were having so much fun, but after a while, I started feeling really bad.
我們玩得很開心，但是過了一會兒，我開始感到非常難過
- Why? Was it your stomach? - No. Memory loss.
-為什麼？肚子不舒服嗎？-不是的  我的記憶力減退
I forgot what I came there to do.
我忘了去那兒做什麼
I don't have the constitution anymore. You enjoy yourself, I'm fine.
我體格不行了，你喝吧，不用管我
Thank you.
謝謝
Pull over.
靠邊停
Good evening. Papers, please.
晚上好，請給我證件
Good evening, officer.
晚上好，長官
Here.
給你
All my papers are there.
我所有的證件都在那裏
Everything should be in order.
應該都是井然有序
- I have somewhere to be. - Hold up. I haven't checked yet.
-我有地方要去  -等等，我還冇檢查
Get out! Out! Out!
下車！下車！下車！
Get out! Get out of the car!
下車！下車！
Get out! Out! Out, I said!
下車！下車！下車！
Get out!
下車！
Put your hands up!
舉起手來！
Let me see your hands. Get up! Get up!
把手都舉起來，舉起來！
Listen up.
聽著
They have Hamza.
他們抓住了哈姆薩
- So? What am I supposed to say? - What are you supposed to say?
-那我應該說什麼？-你應該說什麼？
Hamza will tell them everything he knows.
哈姆薩會告訴他們他所知道的一切
They've forced our hand.
他們逼我們就手
You're going to tell them everything you know, as well, Vural.
你還將告訴他們所有你知道的事情，烏拉爾
Keeping Ufuk in mind, of course.
時刻記住烏福克
Is that clear?
明白了嗎？
Of course.
當然
- How many left? - This is the last one.
-還剩幾個？-這是最後一個
- Name? - Vural Yasl?.
-名字？-烏拉爾·亞斯萊
Go on.
繼續
Take a seat, Vural.
坐吧  烏拉爾
Vural Yasl?... Yes.
烏拉爾·亞斯萊……
Go on. Tell me what happened in Kambura.
告訴我坎佈拉發生了什麼
How did you escape from prison? Who helped you?
你是如何越獄的？誰幫助了你？
Storks.
鸛
Storks flew me away.
鸛帶我飛走了
Then flew me back.
然後又飛了回來
Who would help a poor man such as I?
誰能幫助像我這樣的窮人？
I escaped on my own, of course.
我當然是自己逃出來的
Got myself hospitalized, and escaped from there.
讓自己進醫院，從那裏逃了出來
Your brother Tayyar and his family died in a fire in Kambura.
你的兄弟塔亞爾和他的家人在坎佈拉死於火災
What do you know about that?
你對此有什麼了解？
I don't know much about it.
我對此不太了解
My brother liked to drink.
我哥哥喜歡喝酒
He was a drunk. He drank like a sponge.
他是個酒鬼  他像海綿吸水一樣喝酒
But you can't really help it. You need workers to till the fields.
但真的冇辦法  需要人來耕地
He came to Kambura every year. Found a job to do one way or another.
他每年都來坎佈拉 做各種各樣的工作
They worked, him and his whole family.
他和他的家人一起工作
A fire broke out at their house.
他們的房子著火了
His family died in that fire, including all his children.
他的家人在那場大火中喪生，包括他所有的孩子
That drove me up the walls. I headed to Kambura.
那件事使我抓狂了  我去了坎佈拉
I asked them what happened.
我問他們發生了什麼事
They told me there was a fire, started from a cigarette butt.
他們告訴我起了火，是煙頭引發的火災
I asked the fire brigade and the police. They all told me the same story.
我也問了消防員和警察  他們說法都一樣
There was this guy, Halis. He used to run the fire brigade. He's dead now.
當時有一個叫做哈裏斯的人  他曾經在消防隊，但他現在已經死了
He told us it was a cigarette butt that started the fire.
他告訴我們，那是一支煙蒂引發的火災
That's what we all knew.
那就是我們知道的一切了
It didn't sit right with me...
在我看來有些不對……
It was a tiny house. I didn't get why they couldn't escape.
那是一間很小的房子  我不知道為什麼他們無法逃脫
Then two young men came to talk to me. They were brothers. Twins, apparently.
然後有兩個年輕人來跟我說話  他們顯然是孿生兄弟
- One was named Seyfi or something. - And the other's name, Umut?
-一個叫塞菲還是什麼  -另一個叫烏穆特？
That might've been it. It's been a while.
可能是的，我記不清了
- They're Ufuk's brothers. - Ufuk?
-他們是烏福克的兄弟  -烏福克？
They're actually triplets. Go on with your story.
他們實際上是三胞胎  你繼續說
They told me to drop the subject and go home.
他們告訴我放下這件事  回家去
I asked them why. They told me my brother, Tayyar,
我問他們為什麼  他們告訴我  我的兄弟塔亞爾，
had raped a young girl from Kambura. And not once, at that. Again and again.
在坎佈拉強姦了一個年輕的女孩  而且不止一次
His time must've come, they said.
他們說他該死了
If you keep hanging around, they might decide
如果你還在這裏閒逛  他們可能會決定
to take her revenge on you, they said.
為那女孩嚮你複仇
They weren't talking about someone else.
他們不是在談論別人
They were threatening me.
他們是在威脅我
"Since you're Tayyar's brother, you might die before your time."
“由於你是塔亞爾的兄弟，你可能會死得很早”
"They'll plug you full of holes." That's exactly what they said.
他們原話說的是“他們會塞滿你的洞”
Nevra came to Kambura. We spoke in front of the house, in fact.
內芙拉來到坎佈拉  我們曾在門口說話
That's where we ran into each other after all those years.
過了這麼多年  我們在那裏碰到了
It can't have been more than a week.
就在一周之前
Ufuk found out about it.
烏夫克知道了
Came to me, told me a cop from Istanbul was there to take him away.
來找我，告訴我一個來自伊斯坦佈爾的警察在那裏要帶他走
I asked him what he'd done.
我問他他做了什麼
Asked him why...
問他為什麼
"I burned that house down," he said. "I killed those people."
他說：“我把那所房子燒毀了  我殺了那些人  ”
But he'd been singing the same refrain for years,
但是他多年來一直在講同樣的故事
so I didn't take him very seriously.
所以我冇有當回事
He told me about a girl then.
他曾經跟我提起過一個女孩
There was apparently someone Ufuk had been pining after.
很顯然是烏福克喜歡的人
That bastard named Tayyar raped her.
那個叫塔亞爾的混蛋強奸了她
Ufuk decided to kill him in a fire.
烏福克決定在大火中殺死他
That was the night.
那天晚上
He went to the house and put chains around the exits.
他去了房子，用鐵鏈鎖住了門窗
Then he started the fire.
然後他放了火
I was stunned, of course.
我當然被驚呆了
Who is this girl?
這個女孩是誰？
Whom did Tayyar rape?
塔亞爾強奸了誰？
Why didn't we ever find out about it?
為什麼我們都不知道這件事？
He didn't answer any of it. Just up and left.
他也從冇提到過
I thought he was hallucinating again. He'd never been all there, you know.
我以為他又在幻想  他從來冇有去過那裏
But it all turned out to be true. He really did burn that house down.
但是事實證明  他確實把那所房子燒毀了
Why else would he hang himself?
他為什麼還要吊死自己？
Tayyar's family had been inside. His children, his wife.
塔亞爾的妻子、孩子一直在都在房子裏
All dead.
全部死了
Who could live with that knowledge?
誰可以忍受這些事？
We saw the flames and ran over.
我們看到了火焰，跑了過去
We gathered around the house...
我們聚集在房子周圍
But there was nothing we could do.
但是我們無能為力
Remember that fireman who told us it was a cigarette butt?
還記得那個消防員告訴我們那是煙頭嗎？
The late Halis?
已故的哈利斯？
He had been protecting Ufuk.
他一直在保護烏福克
He must've known what really happened.
他一定知道真正發生了什麼
His brothers must've known also.
他的兄弟們一定也知道
Seyfi and Umut were their names. May God forgive their sins.
塞菲和烏穆特   願上帝寬恕他們的罪過
Do you think your brother might've really done it?
你認為你的兄弟真的有做嗎？
- Could he really have raped that girl? - I don't know.
-他真的強奸了那個女孩嗎？-我不知道
He would never do something like that when sober. That, I'm certain of.
清醒的時候，他絕對不會做那樣的事情，我敢肯定
But drink? Drink turns people inside out.
但是喝了酒我就不好說了
You never know who people really are. Not even your own brother.
你永遠也不知道別人的真麵目  即使是你的兄弟
That's why I left Kambura.
這就是為什麼我離開了坎佈拉
Did they tell you who the girl was?
他們有冇有告訴你那個女孩是誰？
- No, they didn't. - Are you sure?
-不，他們冇有-你確定嗎？
I don't know!
我不知道！
No. I don't know who she was.
不，我不知道她是誰
She must've been really scared.
她一定很害怕
She didn't make herself known.
她冇有讓別人知道
Let me tell you something. If we'd known about what he did,
這麼說吧  如果我們知道他的所作所為
we would've been the ones to burn that house down.
我們才是要燒房子的人
We would've fucked his whole family.
我們會他媽的幹翻他們全家人
I mean, when I say fuck... As a figure of speech, you understand.
我的意思是……當我說他媽的時  那隻是一種說法  你懂的
We would never touch his wife and his kids.
我們永遠不會碰他的妻子和他的孩子
- There's a proper way of doing things. - A proper way...
-做事要有正確的方式  -正確的方式……
You'd fuck him properly.
要好好收拾他
Back then, of course, villages didn't look like they do today.
那時的村莊看起來不像今天
They were properly rural.
他們是農村人
I was in some county in Anatolia,
我在安納托利亞的某個縣，
working as a court clerk.
擔任法院書記員
I come across this murder file.
我碰到了這個謀殺案
I open it up and look at the suspect's statement.
我看著它，看看犯罪嫌疑人的陳述
He's a young man. 18 or so.
他是18歲左右的年輕人
His father takes him aside,
父親把他帶到旁邊
tells him about the blood feud his family's in.
告訴他家族的世仇
They looked into it after the fact. It had been going for 60-70 years.
事後他們調查了這件事  仇恨已經存在了六七十年
Two families, killing each other one by one.
兩個家族  互相殘殺
Anyway, the father says to his son, "It's our turn to take a life."
總之  男孩的父親告訴他  “輪到我們殺人了”
"You're going to do it. You're young, you won't do much time."
“你去做  你還年輕  不用做很久的牢”
The boy's father brings out the gun. It's a family heirloom.
男孩的父親拿給他一把槍  是家族的傳家寶
They've been using that same gun to kill their enemies for 70 years.
他們用同一把槍殺掉敵人，用了七十年
Right there, the father teaches him how to use it.
那時  父親教他怎麼用槍
"Here's how you load the chamber. Here's how you cock the gun."
“要這樣裝子彈，這樣開槍”
"You got it?" his father asks the boy. "I got it," the boy says.
父親問他“你學會了嗎？”男孩說“學會了”
He takes the gun in his hand, and shoots his father. Just like that.
他手裏拿著槍，嚮父親射擊
Doesn't even hesitate.
毫不猶豫
The gendarme asks him, "Why did you do it?"
憲兵問他：“你為什麼這樣做？”
"Why else?" says the boy. "I wanted to end the feud."
“為什麼呢？”男孩說：“我想結束仇恨”
They ask the boy again in court.
他們再次在法庭上問男孩
"We get it, you wanted the feud to end. But how could you shoot your father?"
“我們明白了，你想結束世仇，但是你怎麼能槍殺你的父親？”
"Well," the boy says, "I've always hated my father."
男孩說：“好吧，我一直恨我父親”
"I would've killed him a long time ago, but I didn't have a gun."
“我很久以前就想殺了他，但我冇有槍”
- That's some story. - It is.
-那是個好故事-是的
What about the blood feud? Did it end?
世仇後來怎樣了？結束了嗎？
It did. The other family was baffled.
結束了，另一個家族感到睏惑
The feud ended, but it was the boy that suffered for it.
仇恨結束了，但受苦的是男孩
He was sentenced to life. Isn't that how it always goes?
他被判處無期徒刑  不是一直如此嗎？
The young are always the ones who end up suffering.
年輕人永遠是遭受苦難的人
- It's all over the TV. - Why do you say that?
-電視上總能看到  -為什麼這麼說？
Why hasn't there ever been an elderly suicide bomber, for example?
例如，為什麼從來冇有過一個老人用自殺式炸彈襲擊？
It's always the young who blow themselves up.
永遠都是年輕人把自己炸飛
It's always the young ones. Never the elderly.
永遠是年輕人  永遠不會是老年人
The young ones die so quick, so easily... It's a real pity.
年輕人死得如此之快，如此之輕易  這真是可惜
Their lives have no value.
他們的命毫無價值
How can there be a meaning to life if there is no value to it, right?
如果生命冇有價值，那生命又會有什麼意義呢？
How have we gotten onto this subject?
我們是怎麼聊到這個話題的？
I don't know. I must be getting drunk.
我不知道  我一定是喝醉了
Anyway. I've kept you too long. Give me some flowers and I'll go.
總之  我不會打擾太久了  幫我找些植物我就走
Of course.
當然
I want something for the windowsill.
我要一些東西放在窗臺上
- What would work? - Here. This one. Here.
-什麼樣的？-這個  這裏
- I'll give you this one. - A rubber plant?
-給你這個  -橡膠植物？
- Yeah. You need to water it twice a week. - Alright.
-是的，你需要每周澆兩次水-好的
- It likes sunlight, but not too much. - Of course. Of course.
-它喜歡曬太陽，但是不要曬太多-當然
Mebrure used to love these. What do I owe you?
梅佈魯雷曾經很喜歡這些  我該給你多少錢？
- Don't even mention it. - No way. I want to pay for it.
-別提錢 -不行  我要付錢
- I can't take your money. - Of course you can.
-我不能拿你的錢  -當然可以
I know we're friends, but this is business.
我知道我們是朋友，但這是生意
- But... - It's your first sale to me.
-但是……-這是我們的第一筆交易
I hope it brings you luck. Thank you so much. Thank you.
我希望能給你帶來好運  非常感謝
- You're too kind. - Don't be silly.
-你太客氣了-別傻了
- Thank you so much. Say hi to Cemil. - Of course. Take care.
-非常感謝  給塞米爾帶好  -當然  你要保重
- Take care. - Come back soon.
-保重  -回見
Goodbye. Of course. Thank you. Thank you so much.
再見了  謝謝
Oh...
哦……
The bag...
袋子
Of course...
當然……
Oh...
天啊
That was some explosion.
那是一次爆炸
I must've went overboard with the bomb.
我一定是把炸彈炸了
I almost went back for the bag. I'm starting to really lose it.
我差點要回去拿包  我真的開始忘記了
SAVE ME NEVRA
救救我  內芙拉